<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the Major General of the Parliaments forces in Ireland, with the advice of the Council of Officers.</title>
            <author>Waller, Hardress, Sir, 1604?-1666?</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1659</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B10264</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC"> 80923010</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing W539</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R186193</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">80923010</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 80923010</idno>
            <idno type="VID">191907</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B10264)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 191907)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; 1641-1700 ; 2895:11b)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the Major General of the Parliaments forces in Ireland, with the advice of the Council of Officers.</title>
                  <author>Waller, Hardress, Sir, 1604?-1666?</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by W. Bladen,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Dublin :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1659.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signed: Har. Waller.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Trinity College Library (Dublin, Ireland).</note>
                  <note>With: A true and exact coppy of the several articles (together with the form of the abjuration of the Protestant religion; and confession of the Romish) imposed upon the French Protestants: /  taken from the original, in the hands of Bonaventure le Brun, notary publick of Roüen: Now faithfully translated into English, and published for general satisfaction. Dublin : Printed for John Bentley over against the Four Courts door in Christ-Church-yard., 1685.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Ludlow, Edmund, 1617?-1692.</term>
               <term>Ireland --  History --  1649-1660 --  Sources.</term>
               <term>Duncannon (Ireland) --  History --  Sources --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-01</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-02</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="4" facs="tcp:191907:1"/>
            <div type="part">
               <p>
                  <hi>I A B.</hi> of the Pariſh of <hi>L—</hi> do certifie all whom it may concern, That having become ſenſible of the Falſeneſs of the pretended Reformed Religion, and the Truth of the Catholick Religion, of my free will, and without any conſtraint, have made profeſſion of the Catholick, Apoſtolick, and Roman Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligion in the Church of <hi>L—</hi> in the hands of <hi>P.</hi> In teſtimony of which I have Signed this Deed in the preſence of the Witneſſes undernamed, this — Day of — in the Year —</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <p>
                  <hi>J. P.—</hi> Incumbent of the Church of <hi>L—</hi> in the Pariſh of <hi>L—</hi> in <hi>Roüen,</hi> do certifie that this day being the — of — in the Year — have received the Abjuration of the Pretended Reform<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Religion, and the Profeſſion of the Catholick, Apoſtolick, and Roman Faith, which <hi>A. B.</hi> of the Pariſh of <hi>L—</hi> made in my hands.</p>
            </div>
            <closer>In preſence of
<signed>
                  <list>
                     <item>C. D.—</item>
                     <item>E. F.—</item>
                  </list>
               </signed>
               <signed>
                  <hi>Bonaventure le Brun</hi> Notary Publick in the Palace Yard, <hi>Roüen.</hi>
               </signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>Dublin,</hi> Printed for <hi>John Bentley</hi> over againſt the Four Courts door in Chriſt-Church-Yard. 1685.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="declaration">
            <pb n="4" facs="tcp:191907:1"/>
            <head>¶ <hi>By the Major General of the Parliaments Forces in</hi> Ireland, <hi>with the advice of the Council of Officers.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>VVHereas Lt. General <hi>Ludlow</hi> ſtands charged be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the Parliament of High Treaſon, for breach of truſt and duty; and whereas, not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding, he does from <hi>Duncannon</hi> ſend out ſeveral Orders to the Officers and Soldiers of the Army, ſome whereof have eminently acted againſt the Parliament, to repair unto him, and to recover Garriſons for him, which have already, according to their duty, declared for the Parliament: Whereby (as much as in him lies) he endeavors to put this Nation into bloud, which is all through the mercie of God (except that place he is in) unanimous for the Parliaments ſervice. For the better preventing of which intended miſchiefs, all Officers Civil and Military, and all o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther well affected perſons to the Parliaments ſervice, are hereby deſired and required to ſeiz upon any perſon or perſons that ſhall come out of <hi>Duncannon,</hi> or ſhall be found going thither, without ſpeciallicence in writing for their ſo doing, from the Officer commanding for the Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment before <hi>Duncannon:</hi> And any perſons ſo apprehended, going to <hi>Duncannon</hi> or coming from thence, are to be brought to the next military Officer, who is hereby Ordered to ſend ſuch perſon or perſons in ſafe cuſtody unto me at the Head Quarters.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Dated at Dublin <date>the 11. Ianuary, 1659.</date>
               </dateline> 
               <signed>Har. Waller.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="license">
            <p>Ordered, That this Declaration be forthwith Printed and Publiſhed.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Har. Waller.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Dublin Printed by <hi>W. Bladen,</hi> 1659.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:191907:2"/>
            <pb n="5" facs="tcp:191907:2"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
